Contact

mbrinz76@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/marc-brinsley-msn-ccrn-6a2312152 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Management CCRN ABLS

Marc Brinsley, MSN, CCRN

Intensive Care Nurse at Loyal Source Government Services at Ochsner Medical Center, New Orleans.

Seguin, Texas

Summary

20+ years of experience in several nursing roles and an extensive background as Critical Care Manager, supporting health care / clinical operations and supervising and evaluating assigned personnel. As a collaborative communicator and administrator, I can provide effective solutions and decisions in support of unit efforts. Outstanding capacity to lead and educate staff members, monitor performance, and control expenses, formulating strategies to improve efficiency and productivity and carrying out actions without comprising organizational activities.

My emphasis in providing quality health care services and treatments by analyzing life-threatening situations and acting rapidly to preserve patients' life is evident. My focus has always been to determine appropriate medical care/plans and assist with operations in clinical/medical facilities while complying with established protocols and standards.

I am a qualified Registered Nurse with practice in clinical information systems, health information IT, and nursing informatics with the capacity to train and guide personnel on such technologies. Also, I possess years of progressive expertise in the coordination and transportation of patients to requirements centers / medical facilities across various regions.

Other core competencies include:

- # Trauma / Surgical ICU
- # Clinical & Budget Management
- # Patient Support & Education
- # Basic Life Support (BLS)
- # Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)
- # Advanced Burn Life Support (ABLS)

Eager to explore new opportunities as a Critical Care Nurse Director, I encourage you to view my profile. If you want to learn more about my educational background, my military experience, and my skills, connect with me today.

Experience

Loyal Source Government Services Intensive Care Nurse March 2020 - Present (5 months) New Orleans, Louisiana, United States

Working with Critically III Covid-19 patients in the ICU. High acuity patients that require CRRT, Intubation and sedation, vasoactive drugs, and ECMO.

Flying Nurses International
Flight Nurse
December 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months)

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions
Intensive Care Nurse
December 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months)
San Antonio, Texas

PRN ICU Nurse. Trauma, Cardiac, PACU, and Medical ICU.

Medely
Post Anesthesia Care Nurse
October 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months)
Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Administers diligent care to outpatients via monitoring, assessment, intervention, and continuous reassessment. Ensures that all pre-operatives tests and bloodwork are completed. Confirming that the patient's chart is comprehensive and all paperwork is completed and signed. Duties include prepping the patient for surgery. Interviewing and assessing the patient on the day of the surgery. As a post-anesthesia care unit nurse I provide care for post-operative patients recovering from anesthesia, including general, regional, and local.

United States Army Institute of Surgical Research – Burn Progressive Care Unit

Critical Care Nurse Manager
June 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Fort Sam Houston, Texas

Support the 24-bed Burn Progressive Unit by leading and assessing nursing staff as well as monitoring and evaluating nursing care plans to assist in the implementation of health care services and treatments as necessary. Ensure medical equipment proper operation by completing preventive maintenance requirements as recommended. Participate on seminars and training programs to keep up-to-date about software and applications.

Selected Accomplishments:

- # Prepare annual budget, controlling expenditures and initiating disciplinary actions when needed; plan and carry out nursing informatics strategies efficiently.
- # Comply with The Joint Commission standards, executing nursing best practices to improve staff performance and clinical initiatives.
- # Educate over 75 military, civilian, and contract health care personnel on regulations, policies, and procedures, and evaluate staff productivity; trained personnel on EMR / EHR software and assist with software updates, resolving technical issues swiftly.
- # Provide Health Information Technology (IT) solutions, making recommendations to enhance systems, procedures, and workflow.

United States Aeromedical Evacuation – US Transportation Command

Patient Movement Clinical Coordinator June 2014 - June 2017 (3 years 1 month)

Joint Base Pearl Harbor-Hickam, Hawaii

Coordinated transportation, logistics, and clinical decisions for patient movement across Pacific Command (TPMRC-W). Contributed to validation of evacuation scheduling and operations to Patient Movement Requirements Centers, supporting global efforts with clinical oversight concerning transfer to treatment facilities.

Selected Accomplishments:

- # Collaborated with Theater Validating Flight Surgeons, suggesting adequate actions for complex patient movements.
- # Oversaw clinical operations at USFK Joint Movement Requirements Center, leading efforts for patient movement to United States and coalition medical facilities.
- # Designated as Chief Regional Coordinator Korea, organizing and managing yearly site and training visits for United States Forces Korea

(USFK); served as subject matter expert on patient movement exercise support.

Evans Army Community Hospital – Intensive Care Unit Critical Care Nurse Manager December 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 7 months) Fort Carson, Colorado

Assisted medical staff and nurses in a 7-bed Intensive Care Unit (ICU), monitoring and evaluating patients to develop and implement care plans and assessments in accordance to nursing and military standards of practice and code of ethics. Collaborated with critical care team, evaluating life-threatening situations and determining medical care in compliance with established principles and protocols. Instructed about Essentris, an electronic medical record (EMR) system.

Education

American Sentinel University
MSN, Nursing Informatics · (2013 - 2016)

Hampton University
Bachelor's degree, Nursing · (2004 - 2006)